Know the values.
Know the character traits that you want.
Know the non-negotiables.
You are looking for. And do this thing
prayerfully, not just superficially. You
know, some people have lists.
Lists. Long lists.
In all you do,
please don't marry a fool.
Purposefully single, intentionally
married.
married. Praise the Lord.
So, Paul answered a lot of questions in
1 Corinthians 7, and I will encourage
you, please read 1 Corinthians 7.
Uh especially through this month, as we
go through this month, read 1
Corinthians 7. It will really open your
eyes to a whole lot of things.
Now,
>> [clears throat]
>> my title again is purposefully single,
intentionally married. Purpose is
primary.
Marriage is a vehicle.
See, marriage is good, actually, because
God created it. In fact, if you're
seated there and you have ever
fantasized or dreamed about that day
when uh and you are single, and you have
ever dreamed about that day that you
will get married, God placed that desire
in your heart.
You are okay.
You are what?
The fact that you have the to marry
means that okay, and you are in
alignment with God, because God created
marriage.
However, purpose is primary.
You existed in the mind of God
before a spouse was promised.
Before you existed
in the mind of God.
Genesis 1:26
came before Genesis 2:18.
Genesis 1:26.
Scripture says,
"Let us create man in our own image
to be like us." The New Living
Translation.
"They will reign over the fish in the
sea, the birds in the sky,
the livestock,
all the wild animals on the earth, and
the small animals that scurry along the
ground." That was purpose.
That was assignments
that God gave
in his In fact, at this point, God had
not even created man. It was an
intention in the mind of God.
So, the first thoughts that God had of
man was that man, I want to create man
that will look like me, that will be
like me, and I have an assignment for
this man.
In Genesis 2:18, the New Living
Translation, scripture reads. It says,
"Then the Lord God said, 'It is not good
for the man to be alone. I will make a
helper who is just right for him.' So,
Genesis 1:26
came before Genesis 2:
18.
So, it tells you that purpose is
primary.
God formed you with intention before any
spouse was in view. And that's exactly
what he did with Adam. When although in
Genesis 1, when he was talking about let
us create man in our own image, he had
in mind ma- male and female because
scripture said, "Male and female he
created them." But,
he released first the male, and he asked
him he gave him assignment, gave him
work to do.
And it's in the bid of doing the work
that God has given to him,
God saw that it was not good for him to
be alone.
I will form
I will craft an helpmate that is
suitable for him.
Jeremiah 1:5 says that before I formed
you in your mother's womb, I knew you
and I ordained you a prophet. God
talking about Jeremiah.
So, Jeremiah was still God was saying,
"Even before you were in the womb, I
knew you
and I ordained you. I have I had an
assignment for you."
Imagine Jeremiah, God ordained him as a
prophet. Then
after he grew up, he got married. I
don't know, maybe Jeremiah got married.
Then he entered into because of
marriage, started doing real estate.
Purpose has found another
exit.
Praise the Lord.
Psalm 139:16 says, "Your eyes saw my
substance, before yet unformed, and in
your book they all were written." So,
God knew you.
God planned for you. God had assignment
for you
even before you came
here, to this earth.
So, your calling is not dependent on
marriage.
Your what? Calling. Your purpose is not
dependent on marriage. However,
marriage can enhance it.
Marriage, when it comes,
it
must amplify and should amplify and
advance your purpose.
Are we together here?
So, marriage actually serves purpose.
Marriage should serve purpose. A spouse
is a collaborator, not an end.
In Genesis 2, God brought Eve to Adam as
an helper.
That word helper in Hebrew is ezer. It's
spelled e z e r. That's the word God
used. He said, "I will make him an
helper or an helpmate, that an helper
that is meet, suitable for him."
Now, that word ezer was used most of the
time in the Old Testament in Hebrews for
God.
Are we together?
Was used most of the time for God.
And it means a companion, not just for
comfort,
but for mission.
It's like a co-mission partner.
A an ally, a strong ally, a rescuer,
a protector.
So, God brought Eve to support a mission
that he has created and given to the
man.
Are we together here?
You know, I said earlier that that word
was used most times in the new Old
Old Testament in Hebrew to refer to God.
Psalm 33:20 says, "Our soul waits for
the Lord. He is our help and our
shield."
Another popular scripture, that word
help there. Another popular scripture,
Psalm 121,
verses 1 and 2. "I will look I will lift
up my eyes to the hills, from whence
comes my what?"
My what?
My help comes from where?
You see, two times, help, help. That's
the word ezer.
That is the word that describes the
person that God brought to Adam.
And you know, some of us we are married
and we have this kind of package at
home, but we sideline them in
decision-making.
You have a partner that God has blessed
you with, but when you are
to make decision,
you make decision. You do it alone
without consulting.
Praise the Lord. A spouse is a strategic
partner
in your calling.
Praise the Lord.
So, you should seek alignments.
Seek align That That should be your
focus. Seek alignments. Marry someone
that fits your purpose.
Marry someone that fits what God has
given to you. Marry someone that knows
and that can partner with you in the
achievement of the goals and the purpose
that God has called you to achieve to
walk.
Amos 3:3 says, "Can two walk together
except they are what? In agreement.
Except they agree."
So, marry someone whose vision and
values goes against your calling will
create perpetual tension and drawbacks
for you.
But the right person
will accelerate your obedience to God.
Marrying the right person will
accelerate your alignment with purpose
and the fulfillment of the purpose that
God has given to you.
You know, some people when they were
young, they were vibrant. They knew
exactly where they were going.
Immediately they would enter into
marriage and it would look like marriage
suppressed the calling of God upon their
life. That's not the will of God.
That's not the purpose of God. The plan
for marriage is not to limit you. The
purpose of marriage is not to limit your
calling, limit the the grace of God upon
your life, but rather to help it to
bloom and to increase.
So, your fire should increase in
marriage more than when you were single.
If you marry right.
Praise the Lord.
So, during our court- courtship class, I
remember
one of the things that um
>> [clears throat]
>> you know, we're talking about aligning
purpose.
One of the things that um our counselor
talked about was have a family vision.
Have a family vision. Write it out. You
know, it was an instruction.
We thought about family vision. Because
the truth is two cannot work together
except they agree. So, both of you must
know exactly why God brought you
together in this marriage. And yes,
we did it. But you know, sometimes life
can be life-ing. And that's why when you
come to church every Sunday, we remind
you our purpose there. What's our
purpose again? To
So, if you didn't remember, you know it
because every Sunday you hear it. Every
Wednesday you hear it. And that's how it
should be. Recently, I remember I called
my wife and I was like, "Hey, so what is
our vision again, Sev?
Can we sit down and go back to the
drawing table?" And it's very important.
Because sometimes life can life things
out of you. Just eats and you forget.
But you must be able to come back.
Whether you are 10 years in marriage,
whether you are 20 years in marriage,
whether you are 1 year in marriage, you
must continually remind yourself
what your purpose in that marriage is.
Why did God bring these two together?
There is a purpose. And that's where the
vision comes in.
I need you to also to know that marriage
is a ministry.
Marriage is a what? Ministry. I learned
that also in courtship class. Marriage
is a ministry.
Marriage must be seen and approached as
a ministry.
When you see marriage as a ministry, it
changes your paradigm with
especially concerning all the pressure
that comes in marriage.
Marriage is a ministry.
Ministry in the sense that you are
serving one another.
It's service you're doing.
It's service. You are serving your
spouse.
God brought you together to serve one
another. So, when you come from work
come back from work and you discover
that your partner is tired and you step
in the kitchen to help with the dishes
or to do the dishes, you are serving
your spouse.
Marriage is a ministry.
Marriage is a ministry and both of you
serve one another.
You serve one another. You help one
another to achieve and to grow and to
get better. So, when you see that one
person is weak, you step up and you help
because marriage is a ministry.
Also, we serve our children.
We serve our children. That's what you
do.
You pay school fees, parents.
We just finished one last some weeks
back.
You You pay school fees. It's a ministry
service.
Some people Some parents They can't even
remember the last time they bought
clothes for themselves.
Am I talking about someone?
It's ministry. That's what we call
service.
When you step out to you on the road,
ah, you saw this thing. This thing will
be good on my on my kids. And you you
you buy it. That is a ministry. That's
what you're doing.
That's what marriage is. We are serving.
And also together we bring force
together to then serve our community.
As a couple, you see can serve your
community.
Putting together the resources that God
has placed in your inside, sometimes God
will steer your heart towards helping
someone in the community. God sometimes
God will steer your heart and you will
discuss with your spouse, how can we be
a blessing to this family? You are in a
ministry and you must see marriage as a
ministry.
And through that you discover that
through that your marriage becomes a
witness through which Christ is
glorified, through which honor is
brought to God.
In Ephesians 5:22-23,
Paul described this marriage with Christ
and the church.
That's the marriage
is like Christ, the relationship between
Christ and the church. So, Christ is the
husband, the church is the bride. And
when you read that scripture, you
discover how Jesus as the groom takes
care of the bride.
Through how he saved the bride, how he
washes the bride with the water of the
word, how he corrects the bride. That's
is what happens in marriage. Praise the
Lord.
So, a healthy
covenant marriage is not a distraction
from purpose.
It is actually the purpose. It is to
bring to achieve the mission. It's not a
distraction from mission, it is the
mission. It's not a distraction from
your purpose, it is for the achievement
of your purpose. You know, I've heard
young people who
when love the shark, say, "Oh, that guy
is my distraction."
Oh, you've not heard that before?
Ah, I cannot focus. Secondary school
love.
You know secondary school love, right?
You night call.
How many of us did night call?
MTN.
Aha.
You know
you in the from 11 Is it 11:00 p.m.
till 4:00 a.m. or 5:00 a.m.?
How many of us here confess?
I'm sure you're married to that person
now.
>> [laughter]
>> That That's You see they are still
single.
They are purposefully single.
Praise the Lord. That's not love,
actually. It's infatuation, actually.
Yeah, it's infatuation.
Because real love will not distract you
from purpose. Rather, it will sharpen
you.
Sharpen your focus.
Help you to stay in alignment. Praise
the Lord.
You know, when I hear those things I
like say, hunger never catch you.
When hunger catch you, your eyes go
clear.
Purpose will align. Praise the Lord.
Now,
let's go into the
depth of um my message today. And that's
to the single.
Yeah, relax.
You know, when when we talk about when
we talk about when we when we when the
announcement that we are talking about
marriage
comes out, the heart of some people
beats like, ah,
all through this month we have entered
it again.
You know, right?
They say, ah, but somebody said told me
said said you people are pressing our
neck. Like
you're pressing our neck.
Now,
and that's the truth. Single people face
a lot of pressure, especially in our
world. Yes or no?
Aha, yes. You would That one was louder.
You know, if we we face a lot of
pressure from the world, and sometimes
we we face pressure in church, also. Yes
or no?
There's a lot of pressure, actually. A
lot of pressure in our world for the
singles.
And and the truth is nobody likes to be
a prayer point.
But sometimes life, you know, we face
pressure from family.
Sometimes you discover that no
conversation can be completed without
a reminder that we are still expecting,
you know.
Is it pressure? Is it pressure?
Is it pressure?
And you know, there's also the fear of
missing out.
The fear of
will I ever be like them?
You know, some people have that
thoughts. There's Is that Is Is it
concern?
Praise the Lord.
And in our generation, there's a lot of
stigma
when it comes to being single.
It's like being single is you have
offended the world.
Especially February 14th.
Like single people are endangered
species.
So, that's that's There's pressure from
home, from family.
There's also the pressure
that comes through the temptation to
compromise spiritual standards just to
get out of loneliness.
Right?
Just to get out of loneliness. There's
that pressure. And that's where
cohabiting comes in because you just
want to get out of loneliness.
There's also the pressure of managing
sexual purity in our hypersexualized
world, this world. That everywhere you
turn, there's one ad. In fact, sometimes
when you want to read Bible,
they will still send you ad.
The ad, sorry.
They will still send you ad. and
everything is suggestive.
Am I alone here?
And there is also that pressure of
idealization of marriage.
Some people believe that until they are
married
you are not complete. Some people
project that thought on single while
some single people still think that I'm
not complete until this thing has been
ticked. And you know Satan has a way of
making sure that what you don't have
is the only thing that will make your
life complete.
That was the same card he played in the
garden. You know, right? He played that
same card in the garden.
So Adam and Eve that see
until you eat that fruit or that one
fruit that God said you should not eat,
you are not complete. You are not like
him yet.
And so Satan packaged life, especially
the things that you don't have and makes
glamorize it in a way that makes you
feel like you are incomplete.
You are not complete until you have this
thing.
But let me tell you the truth.
Not everyone will get married.
Is not a good news?
But not everyone will get married. Now,
scripture does not teach that everyone
will marry.
But it teaches that every believer can
live a full, meaningful, and
God-honoring life whether married or
married.
In Matthew 19:10-12,
the disciples of Jesus asked him. They
asked him about divorce. And Jesus told
them that see, if anyone divorce anybody
and marries another woman, that person
has committed adultery. Then the
disciples of Jesus were like, "Oh, so if
that is the case, then nobody should be
married then." Jesus said, "That is not
true for everybody."
Now, let me read it. Matthew 19:
10-12. He said, "Then Jesus The
disciples of Jesus said to him, 'If this
is the situation between a husband and a
wife, it is better not to marry.'"
Jesus replied, "Not everyone can accept
this word, but only those to whom it has
been given. For there are eunuchs,
unmarried people, single. There are
eunuchs who were born that way.
There are eunuchs who have been made
eunuchs by others, circumstances.
And there are those who choose to live
like eunuch for the sake of the kingdom
of heaven."
Three
category of people.
And Jesus says, "The one who can accept
this should accept it."
Are there people that can accept it?
Praise the Lord. And what Jesus was
saying is that some will remain
unmarried by circumstances, some will
remain
unmarried by human condition, some will
remain unmarried by voluntary decision
for the kingdom's sake.
In 1 Corinthians 7:7, Paul react on this
message and he said, "I wish that all of
you were as I am.
Listen.
>> [laughter]
>> Paul is a Paul is a Liverpool fan,
right?
"I wish that all of you were as I am,
but each of you has your own gift from
God." See what Paul was saying? He said,
"Each one of you has
a your own gift from God. One has this
gift, another has that. And what he was
talking about is some one has a gift to
be married, another has a gift to be
unmarried.
So, Paul calls singleness a gift.
charisma
That that's exactly what he's saying.
And when you read 1 Corinthians 7, you
see that Paul elevated that single to
the same level as the married and made
it honorable.
Why? Because they can fully devote
themselves to God and purpose.
That's the word.
They are not encumbered by the things of
the word. That's scripture.
The single have more attention for the
things of God than the married. That's
just the truth.
So, 1 Corinthians 7:8-9
says, continuing that continuing that
that subtitle. It says, "But I say to
the unmarried and to the widows, it is
good for them if they remain even as I
am. But if they cannot exercise
self-control, let them marry, for it is
better to marry than to burn with
passion." The counsel of God is to marry
if you don't have the grace of being
single. But some people have that grace.
Praise the Lord.
And for everyone here
who is believing God for marriage and
trusting God for marriage, this month we
pray in the name of Jesus that your
heaven is open
and your prayer will turn to testimony
in Jesus' name. Now, let's talk about
staying grounded as a single or during
that phase because the state or the
phase of singleness or singlehood is an
important phase in a life.
It is a season.
It is a season. It is not just a waiting
room.
It is a training ground. It is a
preparatory ground.
So, the person you become before
marriage
largely determines the person and the
kind of marriage you will have.
The person you are or you become before
marriage will largely determines the
marriage you will have.
So, I have arranged this for ease of
recollection
in alphabets.
So, I'll just share a few points on how
to stay grounded
in this phase.
Praise the Lord.
And the A is anchored in identity.
Anchored in what?
Your worth
is not in mar- in your marital status.
Your worth is not what?
Your worth is not in your marital
status. Your worth is in Christ.
Scripture says in Colossians 2:10 that
you are complete in Christ, who is the
head of all principalities and power.
You have a worth and your worth is in
Christ.
It's not in your marital status, whether
you are single or you are married.
Your worth is in Christ. Singleness is
not a deficiency.
It's not a defect.
And we must actively reject that
cultural scripts that equate personhood
with partnership.
There is a script
that equates personhood, that if you are
not if you don't have a partner, you are
not a person.
Well, that's not true.
That's not true. So, you must stay
grounded, anchored in the identity that
God has created and given to you.
Know your wounds. Yeah, know your
patterns. Know your callings. Marriage
magnifies who you are already.
It does not fix brokenness, oh.
It magnifies who you are already.
So, you need to prioritize identity
before intimacy.
Prioritize it. Know, be clear about who
you are. Get introduced to yourself.
Know yourself. Leave yourself and live
for God.
As a single. Praise the Lord.
Anchored in what? In identity. The B,
build community.
Build a covenant community. Surround
yourself with people that keeps you
burning and alive.
You know, we are in a generation that
deemphasizes friendship.
Uh just for emotional attachments.
And you see it from secondary school
days, where you say girlfriend,
boyfriend, girlfriend, boyfriend,
girlfriend.
Friends has been added a prefix, boy,
girl, boy, girl.
What about friendship?
Many young people don't even know what
friendship should look like.
Once they have an opposite sex who is a
friend is a is emotion.
And that's the generation that we are
in.
Praise the Lord.
So, you need to surround yourself with a
community of friends, both for
accountability and relationships.
Scripture models deep covenant bonds
outside of marriage. We see Naomi and
Ruth, right?
That's out outside of marriage. We see
we see David and Jonathan
covenanted friends.
You must have people surround yourself
with people that can help you. Surround
yourself with people that know you.
People that can move you forward. People
that can help you in achievement of the
goal of God for your life, especially
when you're single.
Even Jesus surrounded himself with his
disciples.
Praise the Lord.
You can't do life alone.
So, you have to be intentional about
friendship, godly friendship, right
friendship because intentional
friendship guards against isolation.
And isolation is a real danger
in the single life. Praise the Lord.
The C cultivate contentment.
The A is what?
Anchored in what? Identity. B is what?
The C's cultivate contentment. Learn
contentment in this phase.
Why you're here.
Paul
said
Paul said that he has learned
contentment. See, contentment is not
automatic. It's not It's not a value or
a virtue that will fall on you. It's a
virtue you develop. It's a virtue you
cultivate.
In Philippians 4:11,
Paul says that not that I speak in
regard to need, but for I have learned
in whatsoever state I am to be content.
So, contentment is learned.
So, it's okay to grieve what hasn't come
actually. You're waiting, you're
believing God, and all of that. It's
okay. But, don't stay there.
Don't Don't Don't stay there. Don't stay
Don't Don't stay in the face of
grieving.
Surrender to God's sovereignty and rest
assured that he's in charge of your life
and he orders your life.
That anchor will hold you through that
phase. Praise the Lord.
So, be confident and rest assured
that God has a plan for your life.
Praise the Lord.
The D parts demonstrates stewardship.
Demonstrates stewardship.
The stewardship of time.
Steward the gift of time.
Scripture says 1 Corinthians 7:32-35.
It says, "But I want you to be without
care. He who is unmarried cares for the
things of the Lord, how he may please
the Lord, but he who is married cares
about the things of the world, how he
may please his wife."
There is a difference between a wife and
a virgin.
Scripture.
The unmarried woman cares about the
things of the Lord, that she may be holy
both in body and in spirit, but she who
is married cares about the things of the
world, how she may please her husband.
And this I say for your own profit, not
that I may put a leash on you,
but for what is proper, that you may
serve the Lord without distraction.
So, the unmarried What Paul was saying
is that the unmarried have undivided
attention and devotion to give to God's
work.
To give to purpose. To give to life. His
mission His or her mission in life.
And that's
the married might not have full
attention on that. Praise the Lord.
So, this scripture is not just a
consolation. It's a genuine privilege.
The privilege of being impactful for God
in your generation.
And of course, like I said earlier, Paul
calls it gifts.
Not everybody has it.
The heat parts, emotional health.
Emotional health.
Heal before you say I do.
Some people carry hurt everywhere.
Pain everywhere. From past relationship,
sometimes even from their family of
origin.
They carry pain everywhere. And
everywhere they go, they deposit pain.
But before you get to that phase of
marriage, make sure you heal.
Make sure you what? You heal. You heal
from past relationships and trauma.
You heal.
You don't take those things, those
negative emotions, those past those
negative past. You don't take it
marriage. Make sure you heal.
And we've we've seen friends who
they break up today, they married they
they are in relationship tomorrow.
Have you seen them before?
Plenty, have we?
They know them they rush us gang.
You know, although it might look good to
them, but the truth is there is a
healing that you need to go through
before you enter into the next
relationship.
If you don't heal, you might repeat that
process again. Why? Because there is a
hurt and there is pain that you are
carrying around.
So, heal.
It's my need you to take counsel. It
might need you to pursue to to practice
forgiveness. I say forgiveness is needed
in marriage.
Ah, you will say I'm I'm sorry, oh. Even
for the ones that you did not do.
Yes.
You will say you are sorry.
So, you must learn
how to forgive. Forgive yourself and
forgive people.
In this phase, you must learn how to
forgive.
For peace's sake, you will you will say
I'm sorry.
You will say it. Praise the Lord.
The F part, because of time,
faithfully serve others.
Faithfully.
Why single faithfully serve?
Faithfully serve. Practice self-giving
love.
Marriage requires daily self-sacrifice.
And the singles who serve
in church, family, community, who serve
people, they are rehearsing
the posture of a good spouse.
So, serve.
Selfishness is harder to break
after vow, after that vow.
Selfishness is harder to break. Although
marriage will set you up for
releasing selfishness, so that you be
selfless. But if you have not learned
how to be selfless,
you will have a big blow when you get
married.
Praise the Lord. So, start practicing
how to put others first.
That's what you should do while you're
single, while you are waiting, while
you're believing God for your marriage.
Start practicing forgiveness. Start
practicing selflessness.
Because all these are values that helps
for a successful home.
And the G part, grow spiritually.
Deepen your walk with God.
Deepen your walk with God. A person who
is dependent on God
is far less likely to make a spouse an
idol.
Should I repeat that?
A person who is dependent on God
alone while single is far likely less
likely, sorry, to make a spouse an idol.
So,
because when you're married, you know
that last last last last now God own
both of you.
I can't I can't remember how many times
my wife has said,
"I have reported you to God."
If you don't marry right, can they
report you to God?
If you don't marry someone that is
godly, someone that knows God. Why?
Because in marriage, you know that
because you married someone that knows
God, you know that God can reach this
person
even when you cannot reach that person.
You know. You know that if you pray, God
can speak to that person.
I remember something that happened one
time like that and
and my wife said, "Ah,
let's give this person
s-
foodstuff."
And I was like, "No, let's not do that."
And I just I just cut down that idea.
She's a natural giver, you know, it's
part of her gift, but it's not natural
to me, you know.
So, and I had the reason for saying no
reason. My reason is
I don't want the person to be looking at
me
more like my [snorts] helper,
you know? So, I just said
for at that moment because and again, we
were new in that environment. So, I just
said no. I said no. And she didn't even
say anything about it. She stopped. And
then,
weeks after,
I was coming back from work and I just
stopped and I engaged the person. After
talking to the person, I like
I think I will do it.
I went home, packed it that thing, came
back outside and gave it by myself.
>> [snorts]
>> So, when she came back I said, "Ah, I
have delivered the message. I have given
the stuff."
And she just smiled.
She just smiled. Why? Because
I know God.
She knows God. So, you can throw ideas
out and I'm not in that right space of
receiving that idea, but it will not
turn to fight.
I will just go and report you to God
because I know that God can reach you.
So, you must And that's why scripture
says we should not be unequally yoked.
You You have to You have to settle in or
settle down with someone that you know
can hear from God.
Someone that you know that God can speak
to, God can reach.
Because there will be time in marriage
where you will have issues
that both of you will probably be
fighting.
And you will not even want to end it
soon. Holy Spirit tell you, "Say sorry."
Say, "No, I'm not saying sorry. She
should say sorry." Holy Spirit tell her
say sorry. Say, "She no He should say
sorry." She will see the end of the
person.
And the only person that will break
through that cloud is God.
Because the more that thing stays there,
it will continue to attract
some other thoughts, some other
feelings, and some other things. Are we
together? So, you must be spiritual.
While you are in this phase, you must
cultivate the discipline of prayer, the
discipline of the word, the discipline
of fasting, the discipline of community.
These are not things These are not just
spiritual things. They are relational
training
you must cultivate while you're here.
Praise the Lord.
So,
that's A to G, right? The A is what?
Anchored in what?
B is what?
C is what?
D is what?
E is what?
F?
G?
So, my advice for singles, purposefully
single,
know what you want.
Seek clarity.
Not just a pulse, seek clarity.
Proverbs 4:7 says, "Get wisdom.
Get wisdom in all your getting. Get
understanding. Seek godly a godly
uh spouse with intention.
Desperation is not a strategy.
It is not.
Oh, I'm I'm so so so so Yeah, this This
is not a strategy.
Know the values.
Know the character traits that you want.
Know the non-negotiables
you are looking for. And do this thing
prayerfully, not just superficially. You
know, some people have lists.
Lists. Long lists.
In all you do,
please don't marry a fool.
Abigail married a fool.
Nabal. Don't In all you do, don't marry
a fool.
Paul actually addressed this question of
who who marry
in Since that same 1 Corinthians 7:39,
he said a wife is bound by law as long
as her husband lives, but if her husband
dies, she's at liberty to be married to
whom she wishes only in the Lord.
There's a caveat.
Only And you see, this caveat is not
just here.
1 2 Corinthians 6:14 says that you
should not be unequally yoked with
unbeliever.
And you see, unequally yoked with
unbeliever, sometimes you can be
unequally yoked even with believer.
Because there are some believers that
they have different mindsets. Their
belief system, according to the their
own the world, is different from your
belief system. And you wants to You want
to raise children together.
Someone believes A strain, you also
believe A strain,
and you want to
raise family together. How?
So, when you enter into the marriage,
you will now be struggling and be
fighting something that you should not
even fight in the first place.
And some people say that they do it
because God told them.
You know that thing is it's subjective.
And you know, when you come to a person
and say, "God told me," they will just
keep quiet. You say,
If you need counsel, come for counsel.
But when you come and say, "God told
me," there's nothing nobody wants to
tell you. Because it's God that tells
you, right? Go ahead. When you see it,
you will
you will know. It will be clear.
Are we together? Paul said, "Since
In 1 Corinthians 7:39, underline it. He
says a wife is bound by law as long as
her husband lives, but if her husband
dies, she's at liberty." Where I want
you to pay attention to is this, she's
at liberty to be married to whom she
wishes.
Whom she wishes, only
in the Lord.
Whom she wishes, only in the Lord.
So, you see that
there is room for whom she wishes.
And but the room is not so wide that
you can do anything.
It's only in the Lord.
But it's whom she wishes.
There's a story I love in the Old
Testament.
And I've used this story many times
to
discuss with people.
Is the Selophehad daughters. How many of
us know that story?
Please read it when you get home.
Numbers 27:1-11,
Numbers 36:1-13. Write it down, and
please read it.
This family,
their father did not give birth to a
male child.
And this man died in the wilderness, not
out of rebellion, but out of
natural death.
So, in
at that time, in Numbers 27,
Moses was discussing on how they will
share the land.
And it happened that they can only share
the land to male children.
So, these people These girls, these
ladies, they confronted Moses. They
said, "Our father died in the
wilderness, not out of rebellion.
If this goes like this, our father will
not have an inheritance, and the name of
our father will be cleared from the
history. So, we need an inheritance in
the name of our father." Then Moses went
back to God.
And God told Moses said, "What they are
saying is true.
Give them the inheritance that belongs
to their father."
Are we together? Please follow me.
And so in in Numbers 30
the family the tribe that they belong to
that the tribe of Joseph then came back
to Moses like what you have what we have
done we can see an issue that this thing
will bring
in the future. In the future when these
ladies get married they can marry to
another tribe and it means that they
would take their inheritance and join to
another tribe.
Then Moses went back to God.
And God told him
yes
they can marry. Let's read it. 36:6. It
says, "This is what the Lord commands
concerning the daughters of Zelophehad
saying, Let them marry whom they think
but they must marry
only within the family of their father's
tribe."
Are you following what I'm saying? So
Moses is saying you can marry but there
is a confine marry within the tribe.
And that's the same thing that Paul was
talking about in 1 Corinthians 7.
You can marry anyone but marry
within the tribe.
And I'm emphasizing this part that he
says whom she wishes and this part that
I say whom they think best
because many times most people is
because you are waiting for one voice to
tell you that is your husband. That is
Pay attention to the wisdom.
Pay attention to what? To this wisdom.
He that finds a wife finds a good thing.
Finds
and obtain favor from the Lord.
So,
someone ask,
"Should I lower my standard because I
want to find a spouse?"
Another question.
There is a difference between
non-negotiables and preferences.
There is a difference.
There are non-negotiables
and there are preferences.
Non-negotiables like your faith,
character, shared values, alignment with
purpose, alignment with your calling.
Those things must not be compromised.
That's what we see from 2 Corinthians
6:14.
Many times,
physical ideals, cultural preferences,
personality checklists that we create
are often idols dressed as standard.
Many times,
they are our own idols that we have
created. They are caveats. They are They
are standard They are non-negotiable
standard according to God's standard.
But there are some preferences that we
have created, but we need to check them
and allow the wisdom of God to guide us
in the choice and in the decision of
marriage.
And if you are a mature single
here, asking, "Oh, am I too old to
marry?
Has God's window closed for me?" I want
you to know
that God did not set any upper age limit
on his blessing.
Sarah gave birth at the age of 90.
Abraham remarried
after Sarah's death and still gave
birth.
God's blessing
is not restricted by your age.
God's blessing is not what?
It's not restricted by your age.
I I focus on God and what God is doing
in you. Focus on what God is doing in
you. Focus on what God is doing in you.
Know that he that called you is faithful
and he's able to do it.
If you desire marriage and you are old
and you are getting old and the concern
is there and the question is there and
the anxiety is there, trust God.
God will not fail you.
And together in the name of Jesus we
agree with you
under this corporate anointing,
under the authority in the name of Jesus
and the call of God upon this house that
in the name of Jesus your own miracle of
connection starts today in the name of
Jesus.
Can you please bow your heads to pray
with me?
Single, married, can you just talk to
God?
Talk to God.
God, open my eyes for single. Lord, help
me to fulfill destiny
for marriage.
Help me not to limit myself because I am
waiting for marriage. Help me to unleash
the potential, unleash your purpose.
Help me to become all that you have
created me to be even in this phase.
Help me
to become all that you have made me.
And if you are married,
ask that God will give you grace to live
and walk your marriage according to the
purpose of God.
According to the purpose of God, that
God will help you, that your marriage
will be indeed what God wants marriage
to be, your marriage to be. Because God
has a purpose for bringing you together.
God has a purpose, and that purpose is
not just for the raising of children,
although that is part of it, but that's
not the only purpose.
God wants to showcase his glory to the
world through your home. So, can you
declare, "Lord, help me. Help my home to
be all that you have created it to be,
that you want it to be. Help me,
Father."
Can you talk to God?
Can you receive grace?
Receive grace
to be faithful,
to be faithful even in this season. Can
you receive grace?
Grace to be faithful.
To be a faithful steward of God's gifts,
of God's grace, of God's blessing.
Father, we thank you.
Because there will be opening of eyes.
Because there will be miracle of
connection.
Because there will be testimonies
for everyone bearing their hearts to you
this evening.
Father, we thank you.
You are here
You have not accepted Jesus as your Lord
and personal savior.
Or you have accept
But you have backslided into sin.
You know, if Jesus should come today,
you you are not even in the family
because you are lost.
God has plans for your life.
Before I formed you in your mother's
womb, I have a plan for you.
The thoughts that I have towards you,
they are thoughts of good. God has a
plan for your destiny.
You are not a mistake.
You are not here by chance. God prepared
you to be here. So, you are here, you
want to recommit your life to Jesus. You
are online, you want to give your life
to Jesus. You want to return back to
God.
And you are here in this place also, you
want to give your life back to God. You
want to accept Jesus as your Lord and
personal savior. Can you put your right
hand on your chest?
There's nothing to be ashamed about.
At the time, every one of us did this.
This is the only gateway to being in the
family of God.
So, you are here, you want to accept
Jesus as your Lord and personal savior.
Please, can you put your right hand on
your chest and say this prayer after me,
Lord Jesus,
forgive me my sins.
I believe Jesus
as the savior [music]
that takes away my sin.
I I I confess you this evening
as Lord over my life.
And today I am saved.
Thank you, heavenly Father.
In Jesus' name we have prayed.
Heaven is rejoicing rejoicing over this
one, church. Can we celebrate them?
If you said that prayer, our officials
gave you a card and a pen, we want you
to please fill that card. If you're
online,
our officials dropped a link in the chat
room. Please click on that link and
please furnish us with your details.
This journey you cannot walk it alone.
So, we want to walk this journey with
you. We want to help you to grow in your
faith with God. So, please fill this
card and fill that link with your
accurate details. We will send you
resources that will help you grow in
your faith and help [music] you walk in
a way that pleases God. Praise the Lord.
Church, can we rise on our feet?
Can we rise on our feet?
Father, we thank you.
We thank you because your grace is
poured upon everyone present in this
service,
both physically and online and those who
will watch this service. We ask that
your blessing rest upon us. Rest upon
our home in the name of Jesus. And for
every dream present in this place, every
dream home, we ask in the name of Jesus
that your spirit will brood over it and
there will be manifestation
in the name of Jesus. Father, we thank
you. We give you praise and glory. Can
you give Jesus a big shout of praise?
>> Daystar, raising role models.